<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-18T12:57:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/atom.xml</id><title type="html">wadny.com</title><subtitle>it looks good in yellow-that-Kottke-used-to-use-but-it’s-mine-now</subtitle><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><entry><title type="html">&amp;lt;/vacation&amp;gt;</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/22/vacation-end/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&amp;lt;/vacation&amp;gt;" /><published>2004-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/22/vacation-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/22/vacation-end/">&lt;p&gt;So, I got back on monday. QuakeCon kicked ass, people have &lt;a href=&quot;http://r1ch.net/images/qcon/2004&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - QuakeCon 2004 gallery&quot;&gt;posted pictures&lt;/a&gt;. I took a few but haven’t uploaded
    them yet. I’ve been pretty tired lately, and only today finally got around to looking at my blogroll, and I haven’t
    been very interested in it. Maybe after working on web stuff all summer, I’ve exhausted my interest in it for now.
    Look for at least several more days of silence here, and maybe I’ll get back into posting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">So, I got back on monday. QuakeCon kicked ass, people have posted pictures. I took a few but haven’t uploaded them yet. I’ve been pretty tired lately, and only today finally got around to looking at my blogroll, and I haven’t been very interested in it. Maybe after working on web stuff all summer, I’ve exhausted my interest in it for now. Look for at least several more days of silence here, and maybe I’ll get back into posting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vacation, Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/05/vacation-part-i/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vacation, Part I" /><published>2004-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/05/vacation-part-i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/05/vacation-part-i/">&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow morning, my parents and I leave for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mosport.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window&quot;&gt;Mosport International Raceway&lt;/a&gt; for a weekend of racing, featuring the American
    Le Mans Series and Speed World Challenge. This means I won’t have access to anything even vaguely resembling the
    Internet, so there won’t be any posts for a few days. Of course, next week is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakecon.org/&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window&quot;&gt;QuakeCon&lt;/a&gt;, so I’m doing a lot of travelling in the near future;
    however, QuakeCon should have Internet access, so I’ll be able to blog from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;ta ta for now&quot;&gt;TTFN&lt;/abbr&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">Tomorrow morning, my parents and I leave for Mosport International Raceway for a weekend of racing, featuring the American Le Mans Series and Speed World Challenge. This means I won’t have access to anything even vaguely resembling the Internet, so there won’t be any posts for a few days. Of course, next week is QuakeCon, so I’m doing a lot of travelling in the near future; however, QuakeCon should have Internet access, so I’ll be able to blog from there. TTFN…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Great Laptop Saga</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/04/the-great-laptop-saga/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Great Laptop Saga" /><published>2004-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/04/the-great-laptop-saga</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/08/04/the-great-laptop-saga/">&lt;p&gt;Finally, the post you’ve all been waiting for (ha! I crack myself up), the complete, true story of how we got two
    free laptops (totalling about $2500) from &lt;abbr title=&quot;Hewlett-Packard&quot;&gt;HP&lt;/abbr&gt;/Compaq.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started a few billion years ago, when the first amino acids combined to form… wait, too far. The relevant
    story begins a little less than two years ago, back in September of 2002, before my first year of college. I figured
    that a laptop might be handy to take notes on and such, so we (my parents and I) went out and found a cheap Compaq
    laptop that looked reasonable. We might have gotten a better one, but at the time I had also just ordered a brand
    new Alienware desktop to replace my aging 900MHz Thunderbird. As it turns out, the Alienware was even crappier than
    the laptop; it killed a video card, a motherboard, and two CD burners before I finally built a replacement machine
    myself, but that’s another story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The First Signs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laptop seemed to work fine for a while—perhaps a few months—before I noticed that the trackpad wasn’t working so
    well anymore. And it kept getting worse, eventually breaking completely (conveniently before a presentation in class
    I was going to use the laptop for). We sent it back for repairs, which fixed the problem. Or so we thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, I never used the laptop very much, yet the trackpad started failing again. With the warranty about
    to expire and a problem resurfacing, we bought an extension on the warranty and sent the laptop back for a second
    round of repairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Houston, We’ve Got a Lemon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to be a wise choice to get the warranty, as the trackpad started failing again, along with the CD
    drive. Despite virtually no use, the laptop had broken again. In fact, the CD drive may have broken twice; somewhere
    along the way, I lost track. Regardless, this laptop was now underpowered, overweight, and breaking repeatedly. I
    was ready to send it back for a last round of repairs and then sell it on eBay and cut our losses, but my dad
    decided to send a nasty e-mail to HP’s &lt;abbr title=&quot;Chief Executive Officer&quot;&gt;CEO&lt;/abbr&gt; first. A lucky
    decision, that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Turn for the Better&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short wait, my dad got a reply back from HP—and they offered to send us a brand new, replacement laptop, for
    free! Needless to say, we were interested. My dad (I was still at school at the time, so I couldn’t take care of any
    of this) got on the phone with them and they offered us an R3000Z, which we accepted. At some point, they tried to
    change their minds and give us a lower model, but my dad didn’t let them pull that trick. It took them nearly a
    month to ship the R3000Z (specifically, an R3140US) to us, but when it finally arrived it was much more impressive
    than the old laptop. Probably an order of magnitude faster, with a combo DVD+R/RW and CD-R/RW burner, 15.4″
    widescreen display, and a much more solid construction than the old laptop. I’ve subjected it to more use in the few
    months that I’ve had it than I gave the old laptop in two years, and the new one has held up nicely—it’s even my
    primary machine at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;…But Wait, There’s More&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the story takes a weird twist. Maybe a month or so after the R3000Z came in, I came home one day and my
    mom announced that there was a package on the front porch from Compaq. I brought it in and opened it up and inside
    was—another laptop. Huh? I looked at the packing list, and yup, it’s to be a laptop—shipped overnight. From
    SHANGHAI. I still can’t understand how you can accidentally send something halfway around the world overnight—the
    shipping alone would have been several hundred dollars—but they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/products/unorderd.htm&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Federal Trade Commission: Unordered Merchandise&quot;&gt;law on the books&lt;/a&gt; that says
    unordered merchandise is automatically yours (thanks for the tip, Paul!). Apparently it was made after companies
    came up with a scam where they send you unordered merchandise and then tell you to either pay for it or return it—at
    your expense. This isn’t exactly what the law was passed for, but it means the second laptop is legally ours. It’s
    an X1000 series (an X1360US, to be precise), which is actually more expensive than the R3000Z, and the particular
    model we got is worth nearly $1600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, although it took nearly two years, we got two brand-new laptops worth maybe $2500 together for only about $900
    (the cost of the original laptop). If Alienware had handled this as well as HP/Compaq has, I might be willing to buy
    from them again. Also, the quality of these two new laptops is definitely much better than the old one was. The new
    ones are solidly built and seem to hold up well, with no issues so far. The R3160 can even play Unreal Tournament
    2004 at good frame rates, something the old laptop would have failed at miserably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick note to businesses: this is the point of customer support, to turn an unhappy customer into a happy customer,
    and HP/Compaq succeeded admirably.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">Finally, the post you’ve all been waiting for (ha! I crack myself up), the complete, true story of how we got two free laptops (totalling about $2500) from HP/Compaq.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dear God, I’m Old</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/dear-god-im-old/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dear God, I’m Old" /><published>2004-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/dear-god-im-old</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/dear-god-im-old/">&lt;p&gt;One of the ladies who works here brought her daughter in to work today, and she’s talking on a &lt;em&gt;cell phone&lt;/em&gt;.
    She’s maybe 4, and she’s talking on a &lt;em&gt;bloody cell phone&lt;/em&gt;. Goshdarnit, when I was a kid, all we had were
    phones with cords and they were tethered to the wall and our cars didn’t even have air conditioning and the TV had
    maybe a dozen channels and we didn’t have none of this high-falutin’ &lt;em&gt;In-tar-net&lt;/em&gt;… sigh.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">One of the ladies who works here brought her daughter in to work today, and she’s talking on a cell phone. She’s maybe 4, and she’s talking on a bloody cell phone. Goshdarnit, when I was a kid, all we had were phones with cords and they were tethered to the wall and our cars didn’t even have air conditioning and the TV had maybe a dozen channels and we didn’t have none of this high-falutin’ In-tar-net… sigh.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eschew obfuscation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/eschew-obfuscation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eschew obfuscation" /><published>2004-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/eschew-obfuscation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/29/eschew-obfuscation/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stopdesign.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Stopdesign&quot;&gt;Doug Bowman&lt;/a&gt;
    recently wrote an excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stopdesign.com/articles/throwing_tables/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Stopdesign: Throwing Tables Out the Window&quot;&gt;article advocating &lt;abbr
            title=&quot;Cascading Style Sheets&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/abbr&gt;-based design&lt;/a&gt;, where he rebuilds microsoft.com without using
    tables for layout (which would save Microsoft nearly 329 terabytes of bandwidth a year). Shortly thereafter, &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.zeldman.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens a new window - Jeffrey Zeldman Presents The Daily Report&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman&lt;/a&gt; offered &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.zeldman.com/daily/0704e.shtml&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Jeffrey Zeldman: Only defenestrate&quot;&gt;his comments on the article&lt;/a&gt;, where he
    praises it for being short and full of useful content. Unfortunately, he misses an opportunity to simplify the
    message even further. Stealing an idea from Fark (which stole it from a movie), I have managed to reduce Doug’s
    article to a mere &lt;em&gt;seven words&lt;/em&gt;. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Old and busted: tables. New hotness: CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">Doug Bowman recently wrote an excellent article advocating CSS-based design, where he rebuilds microsoft.com without using tables for layout (which would save Microsoft nearly 329 terabytes of bandwidth a year). Shortly thereafter, Jeffrey Zeldman offered his comments on the article, where he praises it for being short and full of useful content. Unfortunately, he misses an opportunity to simplify the message even further. Stealing an idea from Fark (which stole it from a movie), I have managed to reduce Doug’s article to a mere seven words. Here they are: Old and busted: tables. New hotness: CSS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cult-o-licious</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/28/cultolicious/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cult-o-licious" /><published>2004-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/28/cultolicious</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/28/cultolicious/">&lt;p&gt;Photo Matt recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://photomatt.net/2004/07/18/a-foot-of-mac/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Photo Matt: A Foot of Mac&quot;&gt;joined the cult of the Mac&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve considered doing
    this before, but it’s hard to justify the expense of a PowerBook—or even an iBook—when I already have a perfectly
    usable laptop. Also, I’ve heard many nasty things about problems with Apple’s hardware and tech support, plus the
    whole shamozzle surrounding Konfabulator/Dashboard, plus the whole scary cult thing. I’m no Windows advocate, but XP
    Pro seems pretty stable, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://binarybonsai.com/archives/2003/10/16/its-all-about-the-bling-bling/&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Binary Bonsai: It’s all about the Bling Bling&quot;&gt;you can hack it&lt;/a&gt;
    to make it look &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aquaxp.com/theme/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - AquaXP&quot;&gt;almost
        exactly like OS X&lt;/a&gt; if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, I’d still want a Mac laptop except for one stupid, little thing: they only have one mouse button. If a
    computer doesn’t have two buttons and a clickable scroll wheel, I can’t use it. Command-click is not a right mouse
    button. Click and drag is not a scroll wheel. The arrow keys are not a scroll wheel. I know, this is absolutely the
    oldest and possibly dumbest reason people give for not using a Mac, but you can’t just replace the mouse on a
    laptop, and a mouse without a scroll wheel is like a keyboard without a space bar. I can handle Mac OS X and find
    hacks to make it work how I want, but I can’t change the hardware, so I’ll stick with my current laptop for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m on the topic of computer hardware, I’m considering replacing my old &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.samsung.com/au/products/monitors/discontinuedmodels/950p.asp&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window&quot;&gt;Samsung SyncMaster 950p&lt;/a&gt; monitor with a new &lt;abbr
        title=&quot;Cathode Ray Tube&quot;&gt;CRT&lt;/abbr&gt; or &lt;abbr title=&quot;Liquid Crystal Display&quot;&gt;LCD&lt;/abbr&gt;. The problem is,
    I happen to be a fairly avid computer gamer, and I play first-person shooters a fair amount. These games depend on
    the ability to react quickly to what you see, and to do that you need a very responsive monitor that doesn’t have
    smearing issues, which rules out all but the most expensive LCDs, and I can’t really afford the models that are left
    over. However, instead of dropping a lot of money on &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://accessories.us.dell.com/sna/productdetail.aspx?c=us&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;s=dhs&amp;amp;cs=19&amp;amp;sku=320-1578&amp;amp;category_id=4009&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Dell 2001FP 20-inch LCD&quot;&gt;a high-end LCD&lt;/a&gt;, I could spend a lot
    less on &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.necmitsubishi.com/products/ProductDetail.cfm?Product=215&amp;amp;ClassificationFamily=1&amp;amp;Classification=1&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - NEC MultiSync FE2111SB 22-inch CRT&quot;&gt;an even higher-end CRT&lt;/a&gt;
    which would be a better monitor and would definitely not suffer from the quirks of an LCD, but it would take up a
    huge amount of desk space, be difficult to transport, and be very heavy. Does anyone know of an LCD under $500 that
    is a 4:3 aspect ratio (remember, &lt;a href=&quot;/news/during/2004/07/27/an-issue-needing-resolution/&quot;
        title=&quot;An Issue Needing Resolution&quot;&gt;5:4 ratio is bad&lt;/a&gt;), does at least 1280x960 resolution, and can handle a
    modern shooter like Unreal Tournament 2004? If not, it looks like I’ll be looking for someone with a forklift to
    borrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">Photo Matt recently joined the cult of the Mac. I’ve considered doing this before, but it’s hard to justify the expense of a PowerBook—or even an iBook—when I already have a perfectly usable laptop. Also, I’ve heard many nasty things about problems with Apple’s hardware and tech support, plus the whole shamozzle surrounding Konfabulator/Dashboard, plus the whole scary cult thing. I’m no Windows advocate, but XP Pro seems pretty stable, and you can hack it to make it look almost exactly like OS X if you want. Even so, I’d still want a Mac laptop except for one stupid, little thing: they only have one mouse button. If a computer doesn’t have two buttons and a clickable scroll wheel, I can’t use it. Command-click is not a right mouse button. Click and drag is not a scroll wheel. The arrow keys are not a scroll wheel. I know, this is absolutely the oldest and possibly dumbest reason people give for not using a Mac, but you can’t just replace the mouse on a laptop, and a mouse without a scroll wheel is like a keyboard without a space bar. I can handle Mac OS X and find hacks to make it work how I want, but I can’t change the hardware, so I’ll stick with my current laptop for now. While I’m on the topic of computer hardware, I’m considering replacing my old Samsung SyncMaster 950p monitor with a new CRT or LCD. The problem is, I happen to be a fairly avid computer gamer, and I play first-person shooters a fair amount. These games depend on the ability to react quickly to what you see, and to do that you need a very responsive monitor that doesn’t have smearing issues, which rules out all but the most expensive LCDs, and I can’t really afford the models that are left over. However, instead of dropping a lot of money on a high-end LCD, I could spend a lot less on an even higher-end CRT which would be a better monitor and would definitely not suffer from the quirks of an LCD, but it would take up a huge amount of desk space, be difficult to transport, and be very heavy. Does anyone know of an LCD under $500 that is a 4:3 aspect ratio (remember, 5:4 ratio is bad), does at least 1280x960 resolution, and can handle a modern shooter like Unreal Tournament 2004? If not, it looks like I’ll be looking for someone with a forklift to borrow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Issue Needing Resolution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/an-issue-needing-resolution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Issue Needing Resolution" /><published>2004-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/an-issue-needing-resolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/an-issue-needing-resolution/">&lt;p&gt;I was pointed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scantips.com/no72dpi.html&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Say No to 72dpi&quot;&gt;Say No to 72&lt;abbr title=&quot;dots per inch&quot;&gt;dpi&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.cameronmoll.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Authentic Boredom&quot;&gt;Cameron
        Moll&lt;/a&gt;’s sidebar. It’s an interesting article, albiet with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bancomicsans.com/home.html&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Ban Comic Sans&quot;&gt;poor font choice&lt;/a&gt;, but it has a misconception
    in a data table that I need to address. This has become so widespread that I’m going to use inline styles to
    highlight its importance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b class=&quot;big&quot;&gt;Do not use 1280x1024 resolution.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only time you should use 1280x1024 is if it is the &lt;em&gt;native&lt;/em&gt; resolution of an &lt;abbr
        title=&quot;Liquid Crystal Display&quot;&gt;LCD&lt;/abbr&gt; monitor. If you are using a &lt;abbr title=&quot;Cathode Ray Tube&quot;&gt;CRT&lt;/abbr&gt;
    monitor, &lt;strong&gt;do not use 1280x1024&lt;/strong&gt;. Why? I’ll do my best to explain it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitors have something called an &lt;dfn&gt;aspect ratio&lt;/dfn&gt;. This is the ratio between the horizontal and vertical
    dimensions of the monitor, and determines whether the monitor is more square-shaped or more rectangular. Virtually
    all CRT monitors and many LCD monitors have a 4:3 aspect ratio, which means if you divide the horizontal size by the
    vertical size, you will get (roughly) 4/3, or 1.333333333… repeating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screen resolutions also have their own aspect ratio, which is &lt;em&gt;independent&lt;/em&gt; of the aspect ratio of the
    monitor. Fortunately, most popular resolutions (800x600, 1024x768, 1152x864, 1600x1200, etc.) are also a 4:3 aspect
    ratio, so when you display them on a 4:3 monitor, everything looks normal. Here is the problem: &lt;strong&gt;1280x1024 is
        not a 4:3 resolution&lt;/strong&gt;. It is, in fact, &lt;em&gt;5:4&lt;/em&gt;. Thus, if you use 1280x1024 on a normal 4:3 ratio
    monitor (most CRTs are 4:3), everything will be squished vertically because the aspect ratios are different. There
    is no way around this; if your monitor is 4:3, the resolution you want is 1280x960, &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; 1280x1024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s more complicated than this. Many new LCD monitors have a native resolution of 1280x1024. This means
    that the monitor itself is now a 5:4 ratio, so &lt;em&gt;regular resolutions will be wrong&lt;/em&gt;. 800x600, 1024x768,
    1152x864, 1600x1200, none of these will display properly. Confusing things even more, there are now widescreen
    monitors, which are completely different from both 4:3 and 5:4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to run 1280x1024 on a 19″ CRT monitor, and didn’t realize it was wrong, but when I switched to 1280x960 it was
    immediately obvious how everything had been squished. You may not want to give up that extra vertical screen space,
    but trust me: using the correct aspect ratio is worth a little real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do you figure out what the aspect ratio of your monitor is? First, try checking the manufacturer’s website or
    your manual. Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; trust on-screen displays—my 19″ monitor lists 1280x1024 as a “preferred” resolution,
    even though it is dead wrong. If you have a ruler handy, just taking measurements may be the quickest way, and it is
    probably the most reliable. Divide the horizontal length by the vertical length, and hopefully you’ll get a number
    close to either 4/3 or 5/4. If it is 4/3, use 4:3 resolutions like 1024x768, 1280x960, or 1600x1200. If it is 5/4,
    use 5:4 resolutions like 1280x1024 or 1600x1280. If it is something completely different, you probably have a
    widescreen monitor, and God help you because they don’t seem to be standardized; you’ll have to do some research to
    see what works for widescreens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this will save a few people from using the wrong aspect ratio, and leave you less confused than you were
    before you started reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">I was pointed to Say No to 72dpi via Cameron Moll’s sidebar. It’s an interesting article, albiet with a poor font choice, but it has a misconception in a data table that I need to address. This has become so widespread that I’m going to use inline styles to highlight its importance: Do not use 1280x1024 resolution.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elastic Revisions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/elastic-revisions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elastic Revisions" /><published>2004-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/elastic-revisions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/27/elastic-revisions/">&lt;p&gt;You may notice that wadny.com is slightly wider. It seems that &lt;a href=&quot;http://binarybonsai.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Binary Bonsai&quot;&gt;everyone’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maniacalrage.net/&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Maniacal Rage&quot;&gt;websites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kottke.org/&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - kottke.org&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1976design.com/blog/&quot;
        rel=&quot;external&quot; title=&quot;Opens in a new window - 1976design.com blog&quot;&gt;wider&lt;/a&gt; now, and the content column has
    always felt a bit constricting, so I made it bigger. While I was at it, I switched so the columns are now specified
    relative to the font size, so if you make your fonts bigger the line length will stay the same—this is referred to
    as “elastic design,” hence the title. I was considering a larger-scale redesign, and may still do one later, but
    this was enough of an improvement for me to hold off on any major changes. I’ll probably wait until after QuakeCon
    (which is also after my co-op should end), at which point I plan on starting a new windows install on my desktop,
    and then I’ll go ahead and do a more significant website redesign. I’ve considered switching to a packaged weblog
    system, but I probably won’t. We’ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What brought this on? Well, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maniacalrage.net/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Maniacal Rage: Senseless acts of writing&quot;&gt;Garrett Murray&lt;/a&gt; is vying for &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://9rules.com/whitespace/whitespace/first_ever_whitespace_awards.php&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Whitespace: First Ever Whitespace Awards&quot;&gt;Justin Goodlett’s title&lt;/a&gt; by
    redesigning &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;. Relatively minor changes, but his site still looks excellent. I notice he now uses
    relative dates on the front page and actual dates everywhere else, the same as I do, although he did it
    intentionally, whereas I did it because I was too lazy to go mucking around in the archives script again, but as
    long as someone else thought it was a good idea, I’ll stick with it. I’ll definitely have to steal that quicksearch
    thing he has and work it into The Multisearch Box™.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">You may notice that wadny.com is slightly wider. It seems that everyone’s websites are wider now, and the content column has always felt a bit constricting, so I made it bigger. While I was at it, I switched so the columns are now specified relative to the font size, so if you make your fonts bigger the line length will stay the same—this is referred to as “elastic design,” hence the title. I was considering a larger-scale redesign, and may still do one later, but this was enough of an improvement for me to hold off on any major changes. I’ll probably wait until after QuakeCon (which is also after my co-op should end), at which point I plan on starting a new windows install on my desktop, and then I’ll go ahead and do a more significant website redesign. I’ve considered switching to a packaged weblog system, but I probably won’t. We’ll see what happens. What brought this on? Well, Garrett Murray is vying for Justin Goodlett’s title by redesigning again. Relatively minor changes, but his site still looks excellent. I notice he now uses relative dates on the front page and actual dates everywhere else, the same as I do, although he did it intentionally, whereas I did it because I was too lazy to go mucking around in the archives script again, but as long as someone else thought it was a good idea, I’ll stick with it. I’ll definitely have to steal that quicksearch thing he has and work it into The Multisearch Box™.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Have Put Down The Shovel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/i-have-put-down-the-shovel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Have Put Down The Shovel" /><published>2004-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/i-have-put-down-the-shovel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/i-have-put-down-the-shovel/">&lt;p&gt;Feeling a bit better now; after a weekend of hurting myself while doing roofing work, a desk job is a welcome chance
    to sit for several hours straight. I’ve written a bunch of stuff over the past few days, so I’m going to break it
    down and post it in parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what happened during the three or four weeks I forgot to post? Well, the most significant event was my aunt and
    uncle who live in North Carolina coming up to stay with us for a 10-day vacation. It was nice getting to hang out
    with them and see some friends of the family, although the job kept me from seeing them as much as I’d hoped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other significant news is that I am definitely going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quakecon.org/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;OMG DOOM 3 OMG&quot;&gt;QuakeCon&lt;/a&gt; this year. Plane tickets are already booked, and my friends have a hotel
    room reserved. I leave on August 11th and get back on the 16th, so it should make for a nice long weekend. QuakeCon
    should absolutely kick ass; 4 days of gaming and junk food and never going outside (it’s a gaming convention, in
    Texas, in August—we won’t even &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; sunlight), plus I get to meet a whole bunch of guys I’ve known online
    for years, plus &lt;abbr title=&quot;Oh My God&quot;&gt;OMG&lt;/abbr&gt; DOOM 3 OMG and it should be a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the weekend before that, my parents and I are going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mosport.com/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - Mosport International Raceway&quot;&gt;Mosport&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;abbr
        title=&quot;American Le Mans Series&quot;&gt;ALMS&lt;/abbr&gt; race there, which should be fun as always. It’s too bad we only
    have enough time to go to one race a year, but the ALMS is usually entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t recall anything else happening recently (except for the aforementioned roofing work), which is probably more
    the fault of my poor memory than a lack of things actually occurring. As for the website, it’s been getting small
    changes; the Music section in the menu got merged into Site info, the blogroll has been changing slightly and now
    has an OPML version, and the About page has been updated a bit. More changes are coming, eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. The title of this post is actually a play on “I Have Put Out The Light,” a really awesome song by James Holden.
    I’ll share it if anyone requests it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">Feeling a bit better now; after a weekend of hurting myself while doing roofing work, a desk job is a welcome chance to sit for several hours straight. I’ve written a bunch of stuff over the past few days, so I’m going to break it down and post it in parts. So, what happened during the three or four weeks I forgot to post? Well, the most significant event was my aunt and uncle who live in North Carolina coming up to stay with us for a 10-day vacation. It was nice getting to hang out with them and see some friends of the family, although the job kept me from seeing them as much as I’d hoped. The other significant news is that I am definitely going to QuakeCon this year. Plane tickets are already booked, and my friends have a hotel room reserved. I leave on August 11th and get back on the 16th, so it should make for a nice long weekend. QuakeCon should absolutely kick ass; 4 days of gaming and junk food and never going outside (it’s a gaming convention, in Texas, in August—we won’t even see sunlight), plus I get to meet a whole bunch of guys I’ve known online for years, plus OMG DOOM 3 OMG and it should be a lot of fun. Of course, the weekend before that, my parents and I are going to Mosport for the ALMS race there, which should be fun as always. It’s too bad we only have enough time to go to one race a year, but the ALMS is usually entertaining. I can’t recall anything else happening recently (except for the aforementioned roofing work), which is probably more the fault of my poor memory than a lack of things actually occurring. As for the website, it’s been getting small changes; the Music section in the menu got merged into Site info, the blogroll has been changing slightly and now has an OPML version, and the About page has been updated a bit. More changes are coming, eventually. P.S. The title of this post is actually a play on “I Have Put Out The Light,” a really awesome song by James Holden. I’ll share it if anyone requests it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unpredictable won’t bother anymore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/unpredictable-wont-bother-anymore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unpredictable won’t bother anymore" /><published>2004-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2004-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/unpredictable-wont-bother-anymore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/news/during/2004/07/26/unpredictable-wont-bother-anymore/">&lt;p&gt;More changes, which may or may not stay: following &lt;a
        href=&quot;http://www.1976design.com/blog/archive/2004/07/23/redesign-time-presentation/&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;
        title=&quot;Opens in a new window - 1976design: Redesign explained&quot;&gt;Dunstan’s lead&lt;/a&gt;, I switched the front page to
    use “humanized” post times and the time since the post was made. Archive pages still use the old format. I haven’t
    decided which one I prefer, so this may change randomly. I changed the count of comments and trackbacks to be a
    single count of “replies,” which should make things simpler. I added a link to the menu for &lt;a
        href=&quot;/news/latest/&quot;&gt;latest replies&lt;/a&gt;, which has been around for a while but never linked from anywhere. I
    moved &lt;a href=&quot;/about/blogroll/&quot;&gt;the blogroll&lt;/a&gt; to its own page, making room for one of those linklogs that seems
    to be so popular. It’s still under construction, so bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any comments on the changes? I could go either way on some of them, so hopefully the four people that read my site
    will have an opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, this time the post title is courtesy of &lt;cite&gt;Andain - Beautiful Things (Gabriel &amp;amp; Dresden
        Remix)&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>David Osolkowski</name></author><summary type="html">More changes, which may or may not stay: following Dunstan’s lead, I switched the front page to use “humanized” post times and the time since the post was made. Archive pages still use the old format. I haven’t decided which one I prefer, so this may change randomly. I changed the count of comments and trackbacks to be a single count of “replies,” which should make things simpler. I added a link to the menu for latest replies, which has been around for a while but never linked from anywhere. I moved the blogroll to its own page, making room for one of those linklogs that seems to be so popular. It’s still under construction, so bear with me. Any comments on the changes? I could go either way on some of them, so hopefully the four people that read my site will have an opinion. By the way, this time the post title is courtesy of Andain - Beautiful Things (Gabriel &amp;amp; Dresden Remix).</summary></entry></feed>